Erdni Zergetaev

zergetaev@gmail.com +79962590913 Uchinskaya 3, apt 111 Moscow

Summary

Fullstack developer with 5 and a half years of expertise in Ruby on Rails, Node.js (Express.js, Next.js), React/Redux, GraphQL (Apollo). Self-motivated, organized and reliable. Worked both on startups that use bleeding-edge tech and huge websites with millions of users and legacy code. Can work great in teams, especially if using Agile.

Other major skills include: PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, Webpack, SCSS, TypeScript, Docker, Capistrano.

Open to remote jobs, contracts and visa sponsorship proposals.

Employment History

Senior Full Stack Developer

Bonfire • San Francisco, California

05/2021 - Present

- Implemented an airdrops feature on blockchain
- Refactored parts of codebase, increased test coverage with Jest, added granural typings which allowed to fix many bugs
- Participated in archectural decisions such as choosing the tools for caching, background workers, etc.

Remote fullstack developer

Busbud • Montreal, Quebec

08/2019 - 05/2021

Busbud is the world's largest bus ticket seller.

- Added support for selling train tickets
- · Refactored parts of legacy codebase with TypeScript
- Adaption for russian audience: working with translators, designers and marketers to adapt the website to the russian market & laws

Technologies: ES6, TypeScript, Node.JS, Express.js, React.js/Redux, Jest, PostgreSQL, Docker.

Remote fullstack developer

Vayable • San Francisco, California

05/2019 - 08/2019

- Migrated legacy codebase from Rails 3 to Rails 5
- · Added React.js frontend
- · Added JSON API
- Significantly improved test coverage with Rspec, FactoryBot and Capybara

Full stack developer

Krypton Capital 12/2017 - 05/2019

https://jury.online/ - a platform for safe ICO investments. During my tenure the project has successfully raised more than 3 million dollars in investments.

• Developed a web interface for Ethereum smart contract. Work directly with Solidity developers to integrate smart contracts via Metamask Browser

extension.

- · Developed a React.js frontend
- Developed a JSON API with accompanying Swagger documentation.
- Designed the architecture for the platform

Selected Accomplishments:

I was the only developer responsible for developing the dashboard in time before the ICO, and I have succeeded, helping the project to raise more than 3 million dollars in Ethereum investments.

Tech: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, React.js, Web3.js, Bower, Webpack, jQuery, Rspec, Capybara, EcmaScript 6

https://buzz.im/ - a platform for advertising in Telegram messenger. Responsibilities:

- Developed an ad exchange catalogue that needs to work fast (via Rails caching) and not to lose any of the concurrent transactions (via Pessimistic ActiveRecord locking)
- Worked with the developers of telegram bot (@buzz_im_bot) to integrate its capabilities into the platform
- Developed a JSON API with accompanying Swagger documentation, which is used by the new frontend written in Vue.js.
- Worked with with designers on mockups for a design revamp, integrate the resulting HTML & CSS into the platform.
- Helped the marketing department with their job by improving SEO and creating helpful metrics with Metabase.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails 5, MySQL, Bootstrap, StimulusJS, Webpack, jQuery, Rspec, Capybara, EcmaScript 6

https://spika.org - a popular russian concert agency.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails 5, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap 4, Webpack, jQuery, Vue.js

Fullstack web developer

Freelancer 02/2016 - 12/2017

Worked as a freelance Ruby on Rails developer under a guidance of senior Ruby on Rails developer from Zillow Group.

Gained experience working with modern web development technologies and techniques, through the development of B2B solution built with Ruby on Rails 4, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL and ReactJS.

Professional Skills

- Rails
- Express.js
- TypeScript
- Linux
- Git
- Capistrano
- Node.js
- Bootstrap

- React
- Redux
- PostgreSQL
- Rspec
- Docker
- Jquery
- GraphQL
- Stimulus.js

Education

Entrepreneurship

Languages

English

• Russian